<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ANUKRITI GUPTA</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ANUKRITI GUPTA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Incremental Machine Learning</title>
      <link>/posts/incrementalml/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/incrementalml/</guid>
      <description>What is Incremental Learning? Incremental Learning also called as Self Learning/Online Learning. It is a method which allows us to model problem where we have a continuous stream of data coming in. The basic requirement of Incremental ML comes when the training data becomes available gradually over the time which will eventually cost high computation in storing or building the model. The method is applicable for both Supervised and Unsupervised learning techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serving Up Stability - HALICON OPTUM Datahack</title>
      <link>/posts/serving-up-stability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/serving-up-stability/</guid>
      <description>BACKGROUND Service Outage is when system fails to provide or perform its primary function.
PROBLEM The Problem is to predict service outage or probability associated with it at certain point of time
Data  CPU Related – CPUPercent, SystemModeCPUPercent, UserModeCPUPercent Network Related - NetworkPacketRate ,NetworkInboundPacketRate , NetworkOutboundPacketRate Space Related - ActiveProcesses RunQueue PeakDiskUtilization PhysicalDiskIORate PhysicalDiskByteRate MemoryPageoutRate Memory Utilization SwapSpaceUtilization PeakFilesystemSpaceUtilization  Approach  Feature extraction: Time series features are extracted from the data using the date-time field like day, month, weekday and hour etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Experienced Data Scientist with a demonstrated history of working in banking &amp;amp; health care industry, skilled in Statistical Modeling, C++, Predictive Analytics, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning.
Strong professional with a Master`s Degree focused in Mathematics from Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay.
I intend to focus in Reinforcment Learning, Artificial Intelligence and Information Retrieval.
Currently I am working as a Senior Data Scientist with UnitedHealth Group, improving member experience and reducing their hassles through analytics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achievements</title>
      <link>/achievement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/achievement/</guid>
      <description>Awarded Go to the Extra Mile Award, 1 in a team of 60, for initiating a new initiative AES PINE. First and only person in the team to receive a Bravo Award from the client for value creation in an on-site project. Won a Datahack ML competition (1st place among 6 teams) organized by Optum to predict the service outage of an application Awarded STAR Performer Award, 1 in a team of 326, for delivering the Big Data Hassle Free BCS leveraging Markov Chain Model Awarded Team Excellence Award, for delivering the leveraging Machine Learning techniques on 3 Big Data projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/education/</guid>
      <description>Masters in Mathematics, IIT Bombay
 Secured 2nd rank with 9.29 CGPA  Bachelors in Mathematics, Hindu College, Delhi University
 Secured 1st rank in all 3 years of graduation  Online Certifications
 BASICS OF PYTHON NEURAL NETWORKS AND DEEP LEARNING IMPROVING DEEP NEURAL NETWORKS RECOMMENDATION ENGINE  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extra-currics</title>
      <link>/extra-currics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/extra-currics/</guid>
      <description>TEACHING SKILLS
 Experience of 4 years in teaching Science and Mathematics to around 20 students of secondary and higher secondary classes  DANCE
 Represented the department in Dance Competition, PG Cult 2013 (Selected for second level) and Sophie Prod 2012, IIT Bombay Active member of SRIJYA (dance society of Hindu College) and won many prizes among DU colleges  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extra-currics</title>
      <link>/volunteer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/volunteer/</guid>
      <description>INVITED TALKS
 Attended events in colleges like Shaheed Rajguru College of Applied Sciences for Women, Hindu College, and Delhi Technical University etc., on Data Science and Analytics to graduates who are all set to be a part of future Data Science rally.  RLADIES CHAPTER
 Started RLadies Delhi Chapter to encourage women in Data Science enviornment and also help them in getting comfortable with R.  TEACHING SKILLS</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internships</title>
      <link>/internship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/internship/</guid>
      <description>MINISTRY OF STATISTICS AND PROGRAMME IMPLEMENTATION, GOVT. OF INDIA
(JUL – AUG, 2013)
 Statistically analyzed the demographic profiles of India using Census 2011 data Identified various factors that affect population growth IMR with major focus on Empowered Action Group (EAG)  JAYPEE GROUP
(MAY – JUL, 2013)
 Studied the emergence of Derivatives trading in various sectors of Indian Economy and its application to minimize the risk  BANKING MANAGEMENT SYSTEM USING C++</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internships</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Email Engagement of Member • Improved the methodology to define the members’ level of email engagement by including their interaction data from previous years. Also used Empirical Bayesian Model to predict the likelihood of a member opening an email in future
Pah Finder for Screening • Identified an optimized path to target members for Breast Cancer Screening campaign to increase their engagement and to reduce unproductive communications using Decision Trees and Markov Model in PySpark</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers authored/coauthored by Anukriti</title>
      <link>/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/</guid>
      <description>RIGHT TIME TO ENGAGE- RTE
A methodology to identify the right time to contact a member.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volunteer Experience</title>
      <link>/volunteer-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/volunteer-experience/</guid>
      <description>INVITED TALKS
 Delhi University Colleges: Python and ML workshops. MinneAnalytics Conference Minnesota: Provider Rating Score  RLadies Delhi
R-Ladies is a worldwide organization whose mission is to promote gender diversity in the R community. Our goal is to promote diversity and encourage women to involve in the community of R by conducting various events related to analytics, data science and R programming to share our knowldege and experiences together. These events will include: talks, training, workshop, hackathons and projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DERA</title>
      <link>/portfolio/dera/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/dera/</guid>
      <description>This is a Java reference implementation of dynamic event-driven actors runtime aiming at providing adequate abstraction levels and mechanisms for modelling and developing (distributed) event-based systems. DERA leverages the intrinsic loose coupling of event-driven communication styles to support various kinds of run-time evolution and adaptation (i.e., enabling run-time flexibility) while minimizing the non-deterministic nature of traditional event-based applications (i.e., supporting formal analysis).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hyde-hyde</title>
      <link>/portfolio/hyde-hyde/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/hyde-hyde/</guid>
      <description>Hyde-hyde is a responsive Hugo theme inspired by @spf13&amp;rsquo;s Hyde and its variant Nate Finch&amp;rsquo;s blog. It was heavily restructured with modularised page layouts for easier maintenance and modification. Hyde-hyde offers awesome features such as nice colour tone, code highlighting, Font-Awesome 5&amp;rsquo;s sidebar icons), a cool portfolio page, more choices for commenting (e.g. GraphComment, Disqus).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaraMod</title>
      <link>/portfolio/laramod/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/laramod/</guid>
      <description>LaraMod is another modularisation effort to systematically organising a Laravel based project. The idea stems from my struggle to structure a Laravel-based project so that I can work effectively on individual modules whilst keeping Laravel codebase intact as much as possible and also keeping the project&amp;rsquo;s codebase separate from Laravel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/volunteer-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/volunteer-experience/</guid>
      <description>Volunteer Experiencecode{white-space: pre;}pre:not([class]) {background-color: white;}if (window.hljs) {hljs.configure({languages: []});hljs.initHighlightingOnLoad();if (document.readyState &amp;&amp; document.readyState === &#34;complete&#34;) {window.setTimeout(function() { hljs.initHighlighting(); }, 0);}}h1 {font-size: 34px;}h1.title {font-size: 38px;}h2 {font-size: 30px;}h3 {font-size: 24px;}h4 {font-size: 18px;}h5 {font-size: 16px;}h6 {font-size: 12px;}.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>